Guide to the W. B. Carnochan Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
W. B. Carnochan papers
1928-2013
1960-2013
SC0614
Carnochan, W. B.
26 Linear feet (28 boxes)
Papers documenting Carnochan's career as researcher and writer. Included are source materials, drafts, and published versions of his scholarly articles and books, with related correspondence; published book reviews; texts of papers and talks with related correspondence and ephemera; and materials pertaining to his support of the Stanford University Libraries and his directorship of the Stanford Humanities Center.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of W. B. Carnochan, 1999-2013.
Information about Access
Materials in Accession ARCH-2010-102, Box 2 are closed until January 1, 2021. Otherwise the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography
Educated at Harvard University (A.B. 1953, A.M. 1957, and Ph.D. 1960), W. B. Carnochan joined the English faculty at Stanford University in 1960. He chaired the English department from 1971-73 and has served the University as dean of graduate studies and vice-provost, 1975-80, and director of the Stanford Humanities Center, 1985-1991.
A scholar of the eighteenth century, his published books include Gibbon's Solitude: The Inward World of the Historian (1987), Confinement and Flight: An Essay on English Literature of the Eighteenth Century (1977), and Lemuel Gulliver's Mirror For Man (1968). Other works include The Battleground of the Curriculum: Liberal Education and American Experience (1993) and Momentary Bliss: an American Memoir (1999).
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers primarily document Carnochan's professional career as researcher and writer. Included are source materials, drafts, and published versions of his scholarly articles and books, with related correspondence; published book reviews, 1960s-1990s; texts of papers and talks with related correspondence and ephemera, 1977-1997; and materials pertaining to his support of the Stanford University Libraries and his directorship of the Stanford Humanities Center, including a VHS tape of his retirement roast. Correspondents include Richard Ohmann, Catharine Stimpson, Linda Hutcheon, Charles Pierce, Peter Brooks, David M. Vieth, Emerson Brown, Jr., W. J. Bate, Patricia Spacks, Newell Ford, and William Frost. Other papers include his grade reports and papers from Buckley School, St. Paul's School, and Harvard University; listing and appraisal of the Carnochan family papers; and the "American Vernacular" exhibit brochure for the Carnochan Collections at UC Berkeley's University Art Museum. The addition to his papers received in 2006 includes correspondence with Douglas Dennis, an inmate at Angola Prison, 1996-2006; copies of The Angolite, The Prison News Magazine, 1994-2005; and Brigitte Carnochan's portfolio of photographs taken at the Angola Prison Rodeo in 2001. The addition to his papers received in 2009 includes correspondence with Douglas Dennis, 2006-2009, and issues of The Angolite, 2006-2009.
Access Terms
Bate, Walter Jackson, 1918-1999; Brooks, Peter, 1938-; Brown, Emerson, 1934-; Carnochan, Brigitte Hoy; Dennis, Douglas; Ford, Newell F., 1912-; Frost, William, 1917-; Hutcheon, Linda, 1947-; Ohmann, Richard M. (Richard Malin), 1931-; Pierce, Charles E.; Spacks, Patricia Ann Meyer.; Stimpson, Catharine R., 1936-; Vieth, David M.; English literature--18th century--Study and teaching.; Louisiana State Penitentiary.; Prisoners--Recreation--Louisiana.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1928-1999; Accession ARCH-1999-260
  - Publications
    - Articles, Files #1-22, containing drafts, correspondence, published copies, and other items (Box 1)
    - Articles, Files #23-35, containing drafts, correspondence, published copies, and other items (Box 2)
    - Articles, Files #35-38, containing drafts, correspondence, published copies, and other items (Box 3)
    - Two folders of correspondence re articles, 1963-98 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, reviews, and other materials on WBC's books: Sir George Etherege, The Man of Mode (edited by WBC); Lemuel Gulliver's Mirror for Man; Confinement and Flight; The Battleground of the Curriculum (Box 3)
    - Gibbon's Solitude – Times Literary Supplement issues (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Gibbon's Solitude – foreign newspapers (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Momentary Bliss (galleys) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Reviews 1960s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Reviews 1970s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Reviews 1980s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Reviews 1990s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Reviews undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Review of Rawson's Satire and Sentiment, 1994-95 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Gibbon's Solitude – correspondence, reviews, and other materials (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Battleground of the Curriculum: Liberal Education and American Experience (1993) (American and Japanese editions) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gibbon's Solitude: The Inward World of the Historian (1987) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Confinement and Flight: An Essay on English Literature of the Eighteenth Century (1977) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lemuel Gulliver's Mirror For Man (1968) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Man of Mode, by George Etherege; edited by W. B. Carnochan (1966) (3 copies) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Literary journals and newspapers containing book reviews by Carnochan (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Professional Files
    - ACRL, RBMS pre-conference at Stanford, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies, paper presented 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Clarion, Museum of American Folk Art, 1989 – letter by WBC (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - College Art Association, program from 1989 meeting (see page 44) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Conway, John, correspondence, 1995-96 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Council of Graduate Schools, program and proceedings from 1990 meeting (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Curriculum vita, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Grant applications and reports, 1980-87 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Lecture: "Eccentricity and Eighteenth Century England," 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Lecture: "Great Books and the American Disease," 1994-97 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Lecture: "Information, Interpretation, and the Archaeology of the Book" (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Polhemus, R.: Carnochan's verse on his retirement, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - PMLA/Parker Prize/1995 (see page 983) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Retirement: comments by Polhemus, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Samuel Johnson Anniversary, paper presented, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Stanford Historical Society talk on Stanford Humanities Center, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Stanford Humanities Center (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Stanford Humanities Center Annual Reports, 1985-97 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Stanford Humanities Center Bliss Carnochan Lecture (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Stanford Humanities Center, retirement as director, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Stanford University course evaluations, 1997/98 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Stanford University Founders' Day 1997 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Stanford University Libraries Bliss and Brigitte Carnochan Fund, 1991-97 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Stanford University Libraries Howell Award 1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Stanford University – Lyman Chair appointment 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Stanford University – Meier Chair appointment 1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - UC Humanities Institute Conference – paper, circa 1985-90 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Western Society 18th Century Studies – paper presented, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Biographical and Personal Papers
    - Harvard University Class of 1953 Anniversary Reports (10 volumes) (Box 5)
    - Harvard Yearbook 1951 and 1953 (Box 5)
    - Owl Club 1953 (directory) (Box 5)
    - Birth and baptism records (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 740 Park Avenue (New York City): ad and magazine article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Buckley School, reports, 1936-44 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - English compositions, 1942-43 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Buckley Letter, Spring 1988 [75th anniversary] (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - St. Paul's School, reports, 1944-49 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - St. Paul's School, Songs of a Schoolmaster by John Richards, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - St. Paul's School, Sixth Form Yearbook, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - St. Paul's School, Horae Scholasticae, April 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - St. Paul's School, Sixth Form Yearbook, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - St. Paul's School, Dramatic Club – program, photos, copies of school newspaper, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - St. Paul's School, Pictorial, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - St. Paul's School, The Record, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - St. Paul's School, Sixth Form Yearbook, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - St. Paul's School, Alumni Horae, Summer 1949 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - St. Paul's School, Form of 1949, 50th Reunion, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Inventory of Aptitude, 1948 (Johnson O'Connor Research Foundation) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Harvard University, reports, 1950-51 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Harvard University, Eliot House Play, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Harvard University, essay on Lucretius (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Harvard University, honors essay on Swift's sermons, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Harvard Mastery of Stress Study (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - New College, Oxford, correspondence, 1952-53 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Carnochan Family Papers, listing (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Carnochan Family Papers, appraisal, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Carnochan Collections at University Art Museum (UC Berkeley) – American Vernacular exhibit, 1994-95 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Sports clipping re Greg Rice, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Sports, miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Album of diplomas and certificates from St. Paul's School and Harvard (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Album of photographs and letters presented to WCB at his retirement as director of the Stanford Humanities Center, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - VHS videocassettes (2) of Bliss's Going Away Roast, May 31, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Phonograph recording of Carnochan, Nov. 15, 1940, with audiocassette copy (Box 7)
    - Ribbons from Buckley School athletic contests (Box 7)
    - St. Paul's School Athletic Association medal for baseball, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Medal of Charles William Eliot, designed by Leon Deschamps, executed by the French mint, 1907 (Box 7)
    - Baby book of WBC (Box 7)
    - Sport publications: 1984 Olympic souvenir program; 1984 Olympic equestrian program at Santa Anita; LA Dodgers vs. NY Mets, 1988 Natl. League Championship Series; New Zealand vs. Australia, rugby, 1986; England vs. West Indies, cricket, 1988. (Box 7)
    - Harvard University Class of 1953 50th Anniversary Report (2003) (Box 7)
- Additional Papers, 1998-2005; Accession ARCH-2005-115
  - List of Carnochan's publications, last updated April 27, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publication #38, part 1 (Where did great books come from, anyway?) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publication #38, part 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publication #39 (The persistence of the rise of the novel) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publication #40 ("A matter discutable": the rise of the novel) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publication #41 (The English curriculum) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publication #42 (English at Stanford, 1891-2000: A brief history) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Publication #42 [includes Stanford Channel videotape Quadrangles: English at Stanford, 1891-2000] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Publication #43 (The death penalty and prison reform) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publication #44 (Ewald Flugel, Our Anniversary is one of hope) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Publication #45 (Education as architecture: the Yale report of 1828) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Publication #46/49, part 1 (two articles on Hartstonge) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Publication #46/49, part 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Publication #47 (Swift, the canon, and the marketplace of scholarship) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Publication #47, secondary articles (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publication #48, part 1 (The case of Julius Goebel: Stanford 1905) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publication #48, part 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Publication #48, part 3 [includes copies of documents from the Library of Congress] (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, some source materials, and other items pertaining to Momentary Bliss: An American Memoir (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, some source materials, and other items pertaining to Momentary Bliss: An American Memoir (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, some source materials, and other items pertaining to Momentary Bliss: An American Memoir (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Additional Papers, 1970-2006; Accession ARCH-2006-086
  - Alpers, Paul, correspondence, 1990-95 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barker, Nicolas, correspondence, 1988-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coleman, Wanda, correspondence and articles, 1983-97 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Conway, John J., correspondence and memorial service program, 1975, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fine, Gary Scott, correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Krupnick, Mark, correspondence, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mayhew, George: correspondence with Johanna Mayhew Lessinger concerning her father's papers, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Real, Hermann J., correspondence, 1988-98 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Salerno, Nick, correspondence, 1987-2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Schlee, Ann [college friend at Oxford], correspondence, 1996-98 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sitta, Simon, correspondence (Tanzania) with photos, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sullivan, Michael, correspondence, 2001-03 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Trabant, Jurgen, correspondence, 1996, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, former students, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ethiopian correspondence – Tewolde Wudneh (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ethiopian correspondence – Tewolde Wudneh (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ethiopian correspondence – Solomon Afework (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ethiopian correspondence – Marishet Dires, Workeleul Yaregal, Yohannes Wossie (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ethiopian proposal, Abbiyi Addi College, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Publication #43 (The Death Penalty and Prison Reform) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publication #43 (The Death Penalty and Prison Reform) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Publication #50 (Essays in Honor of Bernfried Nugel): text, correspondence, photos (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Angola articles by WBC, including photographs, 1997-99 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Catullus, translations from by WBC, computer text and finished booklet, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chile – lecture text, correspondence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Getty Foundation event (concerning Swift's medical history), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Latvia/Lithuania – sources (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Latvia/Lithuania – lecture text, correspondence, misc., 2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Review of Pocock's Barbarism and Religion – text, correspondence, reprint, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Library Report (article by WBC) 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Times Literary Supplement, WBC's letter to editor, June 29, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Interview re Momentary Bliss, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Interview regarding WBC's MLA seminar 2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Battle of the Books," MLA interview (includes CD), 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy Talk radio program on David Hume (CD), March 1, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Historical Review, correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - American Society of Eighteenth Century Studies, 32nd annual meeting, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bliss Carnochan Lectures, Stanford Humanities Center, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Carnochan – c.v. and bibliography, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Carnochan family photos [scanned versions] sent to Michael Gross for his book 740 Park Avenue [not used] and accompanying correspondence, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Cultural Landscapes" exhibit, SU, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Kelly, George [Harvard roommate], articles, 1970-87 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lamont Library (Harvard), narrative reminiscences 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Review of Battleground of the Curriculum, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - University of San Francisco, Dept. of English, program review, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Yvor Winters Centennial Conference 2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC (and 1 from WBC), 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC (and 2 from WBC), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dennis – Carnochan correspondence, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Angolite; the Prison News Magazine: Vol. 19 No. 5 (Sept./Oct. 1994)-Vol. 23 No. 6 (Nov./Dec. 1998) (Box 5)
  - The Angolite; the Prison News Magazine: Vol. 24 No. 1 (Jan./Feb. 1999)-Vol. 26 No. 6 (Nov./Dec. 2001) (Box 6)
  - Clippings (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Angola Rodeo photographs by Brigitte Carnochan (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Angolite; the Prison News Magazine: Vol. 27 No. 1 (Jan./Feb. 2002)-Vol. 30 No. 6 (Nov./Dec. 2005) (Box 7)
  - Program from 32nd annual Angola Prison Rodeo 1996 (Box 7)
  - Angola Prisoners' Blues (audio CD) (Box 8)
  - Butler, Anne and C. Murray Henderson, Dying to Tell: Angola; Crime, Consequence, Conclusion at Louisiana State Penitentiary (Center for Louisiana Studies, 1992) (Box 8)
  - Butler, Anne and C. Murray Henderson, Angola; Louisiana State Penitentiary a Half-Century of Rage and Reform (Center for Louisiana Studies, 1990) (Box 8)
  - Bergner, Daniel, God of the Rodeo; the Search for Hope, Faith, and a Six-second Ride in Louisiana's Angola Prison (Crown Publishers 1998) (Box 8)
  - Foster, Burk, et. al., eds. The Wall is Strong: Corrections in Louisiana (Center for Louisiana Studies, 1995) [inscribed copy signed by Burk Foster] (Box 8)
  - The New Yorker, April 19, 1999 (article by Calvin Trillin on prisoners) (Box 8)
  - San Francisco Opera 2000-2001, program for Dead Man Walking (Box 8)
  - Angola Prison – October 1, 2000 photographs by Brigitte Carnochan (portfolio) (Box 9)
- Additional Papers, 2006-2009; Accession ARCH-2009-118
  - Dennis, letters to WBC (and one from WBC), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dennis, letters to WBC (and one from WBC), 2008-09 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Email with A. Padgett re Dennis’ health and literary works, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Issues of The Angolite, The Prison News Magazine, January/February 2006 – January/February 2009 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2010-102
  - Jackson, Ian, correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jackson, Ian, correspondence, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Angola prison correspondence, 2005-2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Loken, Rol, correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publication #51, "Utopia and Punishment," correspondence, drafts, etc., 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publication #52, "Who Was Podefar? Swift in the Journal to Stella," correspondence, drafts, etc., 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Publication #53, "On the Tyranny of Good Intentions: Some Notes on the MLA Task Force Report," correspondence, drafts, etc. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publication #54, "Prisoners and Prisons in Reform Tracts of the Mid [19th] Century," correspondence, drafts, etc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publication #55, "Gift-Giving in the Academic Tribe," correspondence, drafts, etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Golden Legends: Images of Abyssinia, Samuel Johnson to Bob Marley, correspondence, reviews, etc., 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stephen Joyce (Box 2)
    Materials are closed until January 1, 2021.
- Additional Papers, 2003-2005; Accession ARCH-2011-082
  - Correspondence and clippings related to The Sad Story of Burton, Spoke, and the Nile (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2013-034
  - The Young Gouveneur Morris: Two Essays, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Morris/Kitty Livingston, Massachusetts Historical Society sources (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Morris: Orations (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Morris: Columbia University sources (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Morris/Friendship (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Golden Legends, re: Sophie Veitch (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journal of British Studies review of The Constitution of Literature, Lee Morrissey, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publication #56, "The Faith of the Fan" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Publication #57, "An Imitation of Gray’s ‘Elegy’, King’s Bench Prison, 1816" (includes drafts and correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publication #58, "Art, Constraint and Memory: Egon Schiele in Prison" (includes drafts and correspondence), 2008-2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publication #59, "Church Monuments" (includes drafts and correspondence), 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-005
  - Publication #55: Gift-Giving in the Academic Tribe (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publication #56: The Faith of the Fan (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publication #57: An Imitation of Gray's 'Elegy,' King's Bench Prison, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publication #58: Art, Constraint and Memory: Egon Schiele in Prison (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publication #59: Church Monuments (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publication #60: Fidus Achates: Swift and Charles Ford (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publication #61: The Tribe of Swift (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Confessions of a Dodger Fan-Research (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Confessions of a Dodger Fan-Book (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scotland the Brave: A Scottish-American Mosaic (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Young Gouverneur Morris: Two Essays (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tewolde Wudreh/Ethiopia (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ben Daughtrey-Correspondence re Angola (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - W. B. Carnochan-CV (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - W. B. Carnochan-Articles and Publications (list) (Box 1, Folder 15)